[
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A company developed a warehouse fulfillment application by using AWS Step Functions. The Step Functions activity workers run on tablets that warehouse employees use. Some long-running activities fail because of problems with individual tablets. These problems include loss of battery power. The application must re-assign interrupted activities to another worker as soon as possible. If an activity fails three times, the state machine should fail.  Which Step Functions configuration will meet these requirements?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["D"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Set the state machine's States.Timeout attribute to 30 seconds. Set the state machine's Retry.MaxAttempts attribute to 3.",
            "B": "Set the task's HeartbeatSeconds attribute to 30. Set the state machine's States.TaskFailed attribute to 3.",
            "C": "Set the task's TimeoutSeconds attribute to 30. Set the Retry.MaxAttempts attribute to 3.",
            "D": "Set the task's HeartbeatSeconds attribute to 30 seconds. Set the Retry.MaxAttempts attribute to 3."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A developer needs to query a relational database from an AWS Lambda function. The Lambda function will be called frequently. The developer needs to avoid the latency introduced by the initial JDBC connection to the database in subsequent invocations of the Lambda function. How can the developer ensure the database connection is reused by Lambda?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["B"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Initialize the database connection outside the Lambda function code as a Lambda function environment variable.",
            "B": "Initialize the database connection within the Lambda function code but outside the handler method.",
            "C": "Store the database connection string in AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store. Ensure the Lambda function handler initializes the database connection within the handler method.",
            "D": "Store the database connection string in the Lambda function code. Ensure the function handler initializes the database connection within the handler method."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A developer built an application that stores data in an Amazon RDS Multi-AZ DB instance. The database performs reads and writes constantly and is responding slowly. The intensive read requests are received unpredictably several times each hour. The application cannot tolerate reading stale data. The developer must increase the retrieval speed for the intensive read requests.  Which strategy will meet these requirements?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["A"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Use an Amazon ElastiCache cluster with a write-through strategy. Configure the application to direct the intensive read operations to ElastiCache.",
            "B": "Use an Amazon DynamoDB Accelerator (DAX) cluster with a write-through strategy. Configure the application to direct the intensive read operations to the DAX cluster.",
            "C": "Configure the application to direct the intensive read operations to the Multi-AZ standby replica in the second Availability Zone.",
            "D": "Add an RDS read replica. Configure the application to direct the intensive read operations to the read replica."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A company has an inventory system that receives sporadic inventory updates from a fulfillment system in the form of large JSON files. While many files can be sent in a short time period, days can pass when no files are sent. The company wants to process these files as soon as they arrive. Which solution will meet these requirements?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["C"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Send the JSON files to Amazon Elastic File System (Amazon EFS). Configure an AWS Lambda function with an Amazon EFS event source to process the files.",
            "B": "Send the JSON files to Amazon Elastic File System (Amazon EFS). Schedule an AWS Lambda function to process the files once each hour.",
            "C": "Send the JSON files to an Amazon S3 bucket. Configure an AWS Lambda function with an S3 event source to process the S3 objects.",
            "D": "Send the JSON files to an Amazon S3 bucket. Schedule an AWS Lambda function to process the S3 objects once each hour."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A company is developing a Python application that submits data to an Amazon DynamoDB table. The company requires client-side encryption of specific data items and end-to-end protection for the encrypted data in transit and at rest.  Which combination of steps will meet the requirement to encrypt specific data items? (Select TWO.)",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["A", "C"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Generate symmetric encryption keys with AWS Key Management Service (AWS KMS).",
            "B": "Generate asymmetric encryption keys with AWS Key Management Service (AWS KMS).",
            "C": "Use generated keys with the AWS Database Encryption SDK.",
            "D": "Use generated keys to configure DynamoDB table encryption with AWS managed KMS keys.",
            "E": "Use generated keys to configure DynamoDB table encryption with AWS owned KMS keys."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A developer writes an AWS Lambda function in Java that calls a third-party API by using an API key. The developer must keep the API key encrypted and secure from casual observation. The API key can change over time.  How can the developer meet these requirements in the MOST operationally efficient manner?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["D"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Store the API key directly in the Lambda function's program code.",
            "B": "Store the API key in a file on an Amazon Elastic Block Store (Amazon EBS) volume. Include code to read the file when the Lambda function starts.",
            "C": "Store the API key in a property file that is deployed with the Java archive. Include code to read the property file when the Lambda function starts.",
            "D": "Store the API key as a secure string in the AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store. Include code to read the parameter when the Lambda function starts."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A company notices performance degradation in one of its production web applications. The application is running on AWS services and uses a microservices architecture. The company suspects that one of these microservices is causing the performance issue.  Which AWS solution should the company use to identify the service that is contributing to higher application latency?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["A"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "AWS X-Ray service map",
            "B": "AWS CloudTrail event history",
            "C": "Amazon EventBridge events",
            "D": "AWS Trusted Advisor performance report"
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "Each time a developer publishes a new version of an AWS Lambda function, all the dependent event source mappings need to be updated with the reference to the new versionâ€™s Amazon Resource Name (ARN). These updates are time consuming and error-prone.  Which combination of actions should the developer take to avoid performing these updates when publishing a new Lambda version? (Select TWO.)",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["B", "E"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Update event source mappings with the ARN of the Lambda layer.",
            "B": "Point a Lambda alias to a new version of the Lambda function.",
            "C": "Create a Lambda alias for each published version of the Lambda function.",
            "D": "Point a Lambda alias to a new Lambda function alias.",
            "E": "Update the event source mappings with the Lambda alias ARN."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A developer builds an application that uses the AWS SDK for Python (Boto3) to query an Amazon DynamoDB table. When the application is tested on an Amazon EC2 instance, the application returns this error message: `An error occurred (AccessDenied) when calling the operation` The EC2 instance is associated with an existing IAM role named myRole. Which set of actions would resolve this error?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["B"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Create a new IAM role with the necessary Amazon DynamoDB permissions. Attach this IAM role as an additional role on the EC2 instance.",
            "B": "Create a new IAM policy with the necessary Amazon DynamoDB permissions. Attach this policy to the myRole IAM role.",
            "C": "Run the aws sts assume-role command by using the myRole Amazon Resource Name (ARN). Obtain the access key ID and the secret access key from the output. Run the aws configure command to store these values on the EC2 instance.",
            "D": "Query http://169.254.169.254/latest/meta-data/iam/security-credentials/myRole to obtain the access key ID and the secret access key. Run the aws configure command to store these values on the EC2 instance."
        }
    },
    { 
        "QuestionText" : "An ecommerce company deploys more than 20 services behind Amazon API Gateway. The interaction between services is complex. Each service can potentially call several others, making performance issues and errors difficult to identify. Some individual API calls have experienced slow response times. The development team needs to quickly identify the underlying causes of the slowdowns. Which approach would MOST quickly identify the underlying cause of performance issues?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["C"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Use Amazon CloudWatch metrics to find the service invocations with slow response times. Configure and use AWS X-Ray to examine these services to discover their performance issues.",
            "B": "Use AWS CloudWatch Logs to find the service invocations with slow response times. Use AWS CloudTrail to examine these services to discover their performance issues.",
            "C": "Configure and use AWS X-Ray to find the service invocations with slow response times. Use Amazon CloudWatch metrics and logs to examine these services to discover their performance issues.",
            "D": "Use AWS CloudTrail to find the service invocations with slow response times. Configure and use AWS X-Ray to examine these services to discover their performance issues."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A company is working on a project to enhance its serverless application development process. The company hosts applications on AWS Lambda. The development team regularly updates the Lambda code and wants to use stable code in production. Which combination of steps should the development team take to configure Lambda functions to meet both development and production requirements? (Select TWO.)",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["B", "D"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Create a new Lambda layer every time a new code release needs testing.",
            "B": "Create a new Lambda version every time a new code release needs testing.",
            "C": "Create two Lambda function aliases. Name one as Production and the other as Development. Point the Production alias to a production-ready Lambda layer Amazon Resource Name (ARN). Point the Development alias to the $LATEST layer ARN.",
            "D": "Create two Lambda function aliases. Name one as Production and the other as Development. Point the Production alias to a production-ready qualified Amazon Resource Name (ARN) version. Point the Development alias to the $LATEST version.",
            "E": "Create two Lambda function aliases. Name one as Production and the other as Development. Point the Production alias to the production-ready unqualified Amazon Resource Name (ARN) version. Point the Development alias to the variable LAMBDA_TASK_ROOT."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A developer tests code running on the developer's laptop. The code is using the AWS SDK for Python (Boto3) to access AWS services. The .aws/credentials file is set up with the user's IAM user name and password. The developer runs the code and receives this error message: An error occurred (InvalidAccessKeyId)  Which action will resolve this error?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["D"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Move the IAM user name and password to the .aws/config file.",
            "B": "Move the user name and password to environment variables.",
            "C": "Replace the IAM user name and password with an access key ID and a secret access key.",
            "D": "Replace the IAM user name and password with an access key ID and a secret access key."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A company hosts its web application backend on Amazon Elastic Container Service (Amazon ECS). The application's Amazon ECS tasks run behind an Application Load Balancer (ALB). The application supports three environments: production, testing, and development. The application uses the ALB to route traffic to the correct environment. The company has configured three listener rules for the ALB to forward traffic to a different target group based on the port number (Port 80 for production target group, Port 8080 for testing target group, and Port 8081 for development target group). The company decides to migrate the application backend to a serverless architecture by using an Amazon API Gateway API backed by AWS Lambda functions. The company plans to use the URI path pattern to access the desired environment instead of the port number. The company has created the Lambda functions for the application backend. Each Lambda function has three aliases (production, testing, and development).  Which option includes the next steps the company must take to complete the process?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["A"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Create an API Gateway API and configure the routes to use Lambda proxy integration. Target the corresponding Lambda function Amazon Resource Name (ARN) that is concatenated with the expression ${stageVariables.LambdaAlias}. Modify the Lambda resource-based policy by adding the permission lambda:InvokeFunction. Create production, testing, and development stages. Add the LambdaAlias stage variable to the corresponding stage.",
            "B": "Create an API Gateway API and configure the routes to use Lambda proxy integration. Target the corresponding Lambda function Amazon Resource Name (ARN) that is concatenated with the name of the Lambda alias. Modify the Lambda resource-based policy by adding the permission lambda:InvokeFunction. Create production, testing, and development stages. Add the LambdaAlias stage variable to the corresponding stage.",
            "C": "Create an API Gateway API and configure the routes to use Lambda proxy integration. Target the corresponding Lambda function Amazon Resource Name (ARN) that is concatenated with the expression ${stageVariables.LambdaAlias}. Modify the Lambda execution role by adding the permission apigateway:*. Create production, testing, and development stages. Add the LambdaAlias stage variable to the corresponding stage.",
            "D": "Create an API Gateway API and configure the routes to use Lambda proxy integration. Target the corresponding Lambda function Amazon Resource Name (ARN) that is concatenated with the expression ${stageVariables.LambdaAlias}. Modify the Lambda execution role by adding the permission apigateway:*. Create production, testing, and development stages. Add the LambdaAlias stage variable to the corresponding stage."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A developer migrates a web application from an on-premises data center to the AWS Cloud. Authenticated customers use the application from many different clients simultaneously, including laptops, smartphones, and tablets. The application runs on Amazon EC2 instances behind an Application Load Balancer. The instances run in an Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling group. Upon initial testing, users report that when switching devices, activity from their previous sessions is not saved.  Which solution will make the session state information persist across devices?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["B"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Implement sticky sessions at the Application Load Balancer.",
            "B": "Store session state information in an Amazon ElastiCache for Redis cluster.",
            "C": "Implement session state information storage in a local file on the webserver.",
            "D": "Store session state information in AWS Systems Manager State Manager."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A company uses an AWS Lambda function to call a third-party REST endpoint. Personally identifiable information (PII) is exposed upon a successful request. The third party that manages the REST endpoint requires the company to change the API key that the company uses to invoke the endpoint every 4 months. The company retrieves the API key by calling an endpoint that the third party owns. The endpoint uses basic authentication (username and password). The new API key is available and active one month prior to the inactivation of the old API key. When the company retrieves the new API key, the company needs to store the key for use in future invocations of the REST endpoint. The company needs a secure solution that eliminates downtime while the company sets up the new API key. Which solution will meet these requirements?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["B"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Store the API key in Parameter Store, a capability of AWS Systems Manager, as a SecureString. Configure rotation to obtain the new API key from the third party and to update the parameter value.",
            "B": "Store the API key in AWS Secrets Manager. Create a Lambda function to obtain the new API key from the third party. Configure rotation in Secrets Manager to use the Lambda function to obtain a new API key. Store the new API key in Secrets Manager. Configure rotation to occur every 4 months.",
            "C": "Store the API key in an Amazon DynamoDB table. Create a Lambda function to retrieve the new API key from the third party and to update the value in DynamoDB. Use an Amazon EventBridge scheduled rule to invoke the Lambda function every 4 months.",
            "D": "Store the API key as a Lambda environment variable. Retrieve the new API key from the third party by using open source software. Manually update the Lambda environment variable."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A developer configures AWS CodeDeploy to install an application on Amazon EC2 instances in an Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling group. Where should the developer place the appspec.yml file?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["A"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "In the root of the directory structure of the application's source code",
            "B": "Directly into the CodeDeploy console",
            "C": "In the .ebextensions folder in the application's source code",
            "D": "In the same Amazon S3 bucket as the application source code bundle"
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A developer wants to monitor invocations of an AWS Lambda function by using Amazon CloudWatch Logs. The developer added a number of print statements to the function code that write the logging information to the stdout stream. After running the function, the developer does not see any log data being generated. Why does the log data NOT appear in the CloudWatch logs?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["C"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "The log data is not written to the stderr stream.",
            "B": "Lambda function logging is not automatically enabled.",
            "C": "The execution role for the Lambda function did not grant permissions to write log data to CloudWatch Logs.",
            "D": "The Lambda function outputs the logs to an Amazon S3 bucket."
        }
    },
    {

        "QuestionText" : "A developer has written several custom applications that read and write to the same Amazon DynamoDB table. Each time the data in the DynamoDB table is modified, this change should be sent to an external API. Which combination of steps should the developer perform to accomplish this task? (Select TWO.)",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["A", "E"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Enable DynamoDB Streams on the table.",
            "B": "Configure an event in Amazon EventBridge that publishes the change to an Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (Amazon MSK) data stream.",
            "C": "Create a trigger in the DynamoDB table to publish the change to an Amazon Kinesis data stream.",
            "D": "Deliver the stream to an Amazon Simple Notification Service (Amazon SNS) topic and subscribe the API to the topic.",
            "E": "Configure an AWS Lambda function to be triggered by the DynamoDB stream and call the external API."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A company is developing an image processing application. When an image is uploaded to an Amazon S3 bucket, a number of independent and separate services must be invoked to process the image. The services do not have to be available immediately, but they must process every image. Which application design satisfies these requirements?",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["D"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "Configure an Amazon S3 event notification that publishes to an Amazon SQS queue. Each service pulls the message from the same queue.",
            "B": "Configure an Amazon S3 event notification that publishes to an Amazon SNS topic. Each service subscribes to the same topic.",
            "C": "Configure an Amazon S3 event notification that publishes to an Amazon SQS queue. Subscribe a separate Amazon SNS topic for each service to an Amazon SQS queue.",
            "D": "Configure an Amazon S3 event notification that publishes to an Amazon SNS topic. Subscribe a separate Amazon SQS queue for each service to the Amazon SNS topic."
        }
    },
    {
        "QuestionText" : "A developer builds an inventory application that runs on employee tablets. The tablet application serves as an activity worker for an AWS Step Functions state machine. The application must retrieve a scheduled task, periodically report on task progress, and report task completion or task failure. Which Step Functions API actions does the tablet application need to make",
        "CorrectAnswer": ["D"],
        "Options": {
            "A": "StartExecution, GetActivityTask, SendTaskHeartbeat, StopExecution",
            "B": "CreateActivity, SendTaskHeartbeat, SendTaskFailure, SendTaskSuccess",
            "C": "CreateActivity, SendTaskHeartbeat, DeleteActivity",
            "D": "CreateActivity, GetActivityTask, SendTaskHeartbeat, SendTaskFailure, SendTaskSuccess"
        }
    }
]